那里没人 那里没人!
There's nobody there, there's nobody there!
救救我 救救我!
Help me, help me, help me, help me!
那里没人!
There's nobody there!
救救我 救命呀!
Help me, help me, help me, help, help!
背叛 毁灭 毁灭 英格兰!
Treachery, ruined, ruined, England!
福尔摩斯 福尔摩斯?
Holmes, Holmes?
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
福尔摩斯 福尔摩斯?
Holmes, Holmes?
你在关键时刻来 华生!
You come as a crisis, Watson!
你自己从波斯盒里拿烟抽吧
Help yourself to tobacco from the Persian slipper.
我过会招呼你
I shall be at your service in an instant.
如果还是蓝色 一切都好
If this remains blue, all is well.
如果变红 就关系到一条人命
If it turns red, it's a man's life.
果然不出我所料
I thought as much.
哈德森夫人!
Mrs. Hudson!
请找一下比利
Would you find Billy, please,
告诉他立即发送这份电报
and tell him to dispatch these telegrams without delay.
谢谢
Thank you.
哦 请坐 华生
Oh, Sit down, Watson.
一件平淡无奇的谋杀案!
A commonplace little murder!
我猜想你有更有趣的事情
You have something more interesting, I fancy.
你总能给我带来有趣罪案
You are the stormy petrel of crime.
华生 是什么?
Watson, what is it?
一位校友给我寄了封信
I've had a letter from a boy I was at school with.
我认为你应该读读
I think you should read it.
珀西・费普 聪明的小孩
Percy Phelps, brilliant boy,
摘走学校设立的所有奖项
carried off every prize the school had to offer,
到了剑桥也初获成功
went on to fresh triumphs at Cambridge.
我承认
I must confess,
我完全不记得他了 直到收到这个
he'd passed completely out of my mind until this.
亲爱的华生
"My Dear Watson:
我确信你还记得 "蝌蚪"费普
I have no doubt you remember Tadpole Phelps,
当你在五年级时 我读三年级
who was in the third form when you were in the fifth.
你有可能已经听说了
It's possible you may have heard
我通过我叔叔的关系
that through my uncle's influence
在外交部谋得一份美差
I obtained a good appointment at the Foreign Office. "
他的叔叔是霍德赫斯勋爵
His uncle's Lord Holdhurst.
我备受信任和尊敬
"And that I was in a position of trust and honor
可一场突如其来的厄运毁了我的前程
till a horrible misfortune came suddenly to blast my career."
他的贵戚无助于他的学校生活
Yes, his gaudy connections did him little good at school.
对于我们 刺激的是
It seemed to us a piquant thing
在操场上追他
to chevy him about the playground,
用棍子敲打他
hit him over the shins with a wicket.
你能带你的朋友福尔摩斯先生
"Do you think you could bring your friend Mr. Holmes
来跟我见面吗?
down to see me?"
信上没多说什么
That doesn't tell us much.
几乎没有
Hardly anything.
但这笔迹很有趣 是女人的笔迹
But the writing is of interest, it is a woman's.
不 不 是男人的 我肯定
No, no, a man's, surely.
不是 是女人的
No, a woman's.
在案情的开端
At the commencement of a case
你总要了解这情况
it is always something to know
委托人和某人关系亲密
that a client is in close contact with someone who,
而那人无论善恶 总有不寻常的个性
for good or evil, has an exceptional nature.
你感兴趣了?
You're interested?
的确
Indeed.
如果你准备好了 我们就马上
Well, if you are ready, let us start for
动身前往沃金的石南坡山庄
Briarbrae House Woking, at once.
我的业务...
Well, my practice-
哦 哦 哦 哦!
Oh, oh, oh, oh!
你的业务比我的案件还有趣?
Well, I mean, if your cases  are more interesting than mine.
我只是想说
I was gonna say,
我的业务在一两天内就能办妥
my practice would do very well for a day or two.
现在是一年中最清淡的时候
It's the slackest time of the year.
好极了
Excellent.
那我们见见那位遭遇不幸
Then let us visit this diplomatist
的外交官吧
who is in such evil case,
还有照他口述写这封信的女士
and the lady to whom he dictates his letters.
哈德森夫人 开水!
Mrs. Hudson, hot water!
啊 罗斯
Ah, Rose.
帮我看着这个好吗? 这是好东西
Check this for me, would you? That's a good love.
夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生?
Mr. Sherlock Holmes?
这是我的同事和朋友 华生医生
And this is my colleague and friend, Dr. Watson.
华生医生 很高兴你的到来
Dr. Watson, I'm so glad you've come.
珀西一早上都在打听你 可怜的家伙
Percy's been inquiring after you all morning, poor chap.
我觉得 你不是这个家的成员吧?
I perceive that you, yourself, are not a member of the family?
当然 你看到我的姓名首字母JH
Of course, you see my JH monogram.
我一时还以为你做了些聪明的事
Now, for a moment I thought you'd done something clever.
我的名字是约瑟・哈里森
Joseph Harrison is my name,
珀西成为我妹妹安妮的未婚夫
and since Percy is betrothed to my sister Annie,
我因此至少成了他的一个姻亲
I shall at least be a relation by marriage.
你能在他房间找到她
You'll find her in his room,
她已经照料他两个月了
she's been nursing him these past two months.
罗斯 回屋
Rose, in the house.
听 他们来了
Now, listen, they're here.
我要回避吗?
Shall I leave?
不要
No, no.
亲爱的华生 我都认不出你了
My dear Watson, I should never have known you
你留着胡子
under that mustache,
我敢说你也不能肯定认出我
and I daresay you wouldn't be prepared to swear to me.
没 你还是那个可爱的"蝌蚪"
Not at all, still the same dear old Tadpole.
我想这位就是你著名的朋友
And this, I presume, is your celebrated friend?
这位是夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Sherlock Holmes,
这位是珀西・费普先生
Mr. Percy Phelps.
我则是哈里森小姐
And I'm Miss Harrison.
我未婚妻 也是我的看护
My fiancee and my nurse.
请坐
Please, sit down.
我让福尔摩斯看了你给我写的信
I, uh, I showed Holmes the letter that you wrote to me.
是的 正如我希望的
Yes, I hoped you would.
只有粗略内容
It was rather short on detail.
那么我开门见山好了
Then let me get straight to the point.
我在外交部当办事员
I work as a clerk in the Foreign Office.
我叔叔是霍德赫斯勋爵
My uncle is Lord Holdhurst.
他成为外交部长后 他信任我
When he became Foreign Minister, he gave me,
偶尔会给我一些棘手的任务
ocassional delicate missions of trust,
我总能成功完成
which I always managed to conduct successfully.
我知道你能做到 老朋友
I'm sure you did, old chap.
请继续 费普先生
Pray, continue, Mr. Phelps.
大概十周前
Nearly ten weeks ago,
5月23日晚
it was the evening of the 23rd of May,
他把我叫进他的私人办公室
he called me into his private room.
啊 珀西 我亲爱的孩子!
Ah, Percy, my dear boy!
晚上好 先生
Good evening, sir.
你听说了英格兰和意大利
You've heard of the Naval Treaty
刚刚签订的海军协定吗?
that has just been drawn up between England and Italy?
先生 我在报刊上看到传闻
I've read rumors in the press, sir.
非常不幸
Most regrettable,
而且至关重要的是
and it is of the utmost importance
不能再透露出风声了
that nothing further should leak out.
法国和俄国大使馆
The French and Russian embassies
会花巨款以探听文件内容
would pay an immense sum to learn its contents.
这是原件
This is the original.
若不是非常需要抄本的话
It should not leave my bureau
我不会让它离开我的办公桌
were it not absolutely necessary to have it copied.
直接拿到你的办公室锁起来
Take it straight to your office and lock it up.
在别人下班后你留下来
Now, remain behind when the others go,
以方便你抄写
so that you can work at your leisure
这样就不怕被窥视
and without fear of being overlooked.
当你抄完后
And when you have finished,
再把原件和抄本锁进你办公桌里
relock both the original and the draft in your own desk,
明早亲自交到我手上
and hand them over to me personally tomorrow morning.
小心谨慎 侄儿
The very greatest care, Nephew.
您放心 先生
You may rely on it, sir.
这份协定
This treaty,
你能更精确描述其性质吗?
can you be more precise as to its nature?
其纲要规定了在法国海军
Well, in outline it defined the position of Great Britain
于地中海对意大利
towards the Triple Alliance
占完全优势时
in the event of the French fleet
大不列颠在三国同盟的立场
gaining complete ascendancy over Italy in the Mediterranean.
我直接回到办公室
I returned straight to my office
发现一名同事
where I found a colleague of mine,
查尔斯・戈罗先生还在工作
Mr. Charles Gorot, still working.
伙计
Well, chap,
你叔叔找你干嘛?
what did Uncle want?
为了祝贺我订婚了
To congratulate me on my engagement.
了不起
Splendid.
没别的?
Nothing else?
还让我复写某份渔业纠纷
Some fishing dispute he wanted me to copy.
你还在解决保加利亚问题 是吧?
You're not still on that Bulgarian piece, are you?
那个特别繁琐而且累人
It's extremely long-winded and tiresome,
我今晚可要累坏了
and I am fagged out for the night.
你又要加班?
You working late again?
就一点事儿
Just a few things.
你要学会放松 老鬼
You want to slack off a bit, old man.
有野心是好事
Ambition is a fine thing and all that,
但可别冷落了美丽的哈里森小姐
but do not neglect the beautiful Miss Harrison.
其他小伙子会趁虚而入哦
Some other chap might step in.
她不会考虑你的 查尔斯
She wouldn't have you, Charles.
可不是我 老鬼
Well, not me, old man.
我已经有了黛芬妮
I've got my Daphne.
晚安
Goodnight to you.
Goodnight.
你肯定你工作前他就离开了?
You made sure that he was gone before you started work?
非常确定 而且我尽快抄写了
Quite sure, and I copied as fast as I could,
因为我知道我未婚妻的哥哥约瑟
for I knew that Joseph, my fiancee's brother-
我们在院子里见到他
We met him in the garden.
他在城里
He was in town,
要赶11点的火车返回沃金
and was traveling back to Woking by the 11:00 o'clock train.
可能的话我想赶这趟车
And I wanted to catch it, if possible.
但文件很长?
But it was a long document?
而且用法文写的
Written in French.
9点时 我感觉昏昏欲睡
By 9:00 o'clock, I was feeling drowsy
仅仅完成三分之一
and scarcely a third of the way through.
我想喝杯咖啡也许可以提神
I thought a cup of coffee might clear my brain,
所以我拉铃叫了夜间值班的专员
so I rang the commissioner who stays on duty all night
他在楼梯下面的一间门房里
in a small lodge at the bottom of the stairs.
让我吃惊的是 传到的是个女人
To my surprise, it was a woman who answered the summons.
对不起 我想叫坦盖先生
I'm sorry, I was ringing for Mr. Tangey.
我是他老婆 先生
I'm his wife, sir,
我在这栋楼内做杂务
I do the char work in this building.
啊 我想你能不能给我冲杯咖啡
Ah, well, I was wondering if you might bring me a cup of coffee.
我去问问他 先生
I'll go and ask him, sir.
这个女人
This woman,
你在楼里从没见过吗?
you've never noticed her in the building before?
没有
Never.
咖啡过了很久也没来 所以我下楼去看看
The coffee was some time coming, so I went down to investigate.
大意地离开了房间
Leaving the room unguarded?
是的
Yes.
我发现坦盖睡着了
I found Tangey-asleep.
费普先生 非常抱歉 先生
Mr. Phelps, sir, I'm very sorry, sir.
我一定是刚睡着不久
I must have just dropped off for a moment.
你的咖啡 先生
Your coffee, sir.
如果你在这里 先生 那是谁在拉铃?
Well, if you're here, sir, who's ringing the bell?
拉铃 什么拉铃?
Bell, what bell is it?
这个是你办公室的铃声 先生
It's the bell in the room in which you're working, sir.
你跑上楼
You ran back upstairs
文件从你桌上消失了
and the document was gone from your desk.
是的!
Yes!
天啊 不
God no-
你经过时没人在走廊?
You passed no one in the corridor?
没人 没有人!
No one, there was no one!
房间里 走廊里
And the room and the corridor
一切都是我离开时那样
all seemed exactly as I'd left it!
珀西粗略画了整栋楼的图纸 福尔摩斯先生
Percy has drawn a rough chart of the building, Mr. Holmes,
他认为可能会用到
which he thought might be of use.
是的 没错 那很重要 福尔摩斯先生
Yes, yes, that's of the utmost importance, Mr. Holmes.
是的 我想我很明白了
Yes, I think I quite follow it.
你发现失窃事件后做了什么?
On your discovery of the theft, what did you do then?
我立即察觉到
Well, I recognized in an instant
小偷肯定是从侧门进来的
the thief must have come up through the side door.
在这里
This one here.
是的 那当然 如果他从正门来
Yes, of course. Well, you'd have met him
你会碰到他的
if he'd come the other way.
那你确信他们没躲藏在
And you are satisfied that they could not have been concealed
办公室或走廊里?
in the room or in the corridor?
绝对不可能
Absolutely impossible.
其他门都锁着
All the other doors were locked.
严格的外交部制度
Strict Foreign Office regulations.
根本没什么藏身处
There was no cover at all.
连一只老鼠都无法躲藏
A rat couldn't have concealed himself there.
坦盖和我都跑了出去
Tangey and I both rushed out
奔下通向查尔斯街的楼梯
down the stairs that lead into Charles Street.
费普先生!
Mr. Phelps!
底下的门关着 但没锁
The door at the bottom was closed, unlocked.
当时很黑 下着雨
It was dark, raining.
没有人!
There was no one!
但我清楚地记得当时大笨钟是45分
But I distinctly remember the three-quarters of Big Ben.
9点45分
A quarter to ten.
这个很重要
That is of enormous importance.
他们去到这里 你看 福尔摩斯
They came out here, you see, Holmes.
在街角我们看到巡警
On the corner we found a policeman,
但45分这个时间除了值班员老婆
but he'd seen no one leave the building in the last
他没看到任何人离开大楼
quarter of an hour except for the Commissioner's wife,
我们跑过白厅(伦敦主街道)
so we ran through to Whitehall.
那里车水马龙 人来人往
It was full of traffic, people coming and going,
阴雨之夜 人人都想找到一个
all only too eager to find a place of shelter on
躲雨的地方
so wet a night.
没闲人告诉你有谁经过?
No lounger to tell you who'd passed?
没有
None.
整晚都在下雨吗?
Had it been raining all evening?
从7点开始
Since about 7:00.
啊 这一连串事件
Ah, this chain of events
真是非同寻常地有趣
is certainly of extraordinary interest.
然后你回办公室
And so you returned to the office,
我猜想你检查了一遍
examined it, I presume,
想看入侵者是否留下任何痕迹
to see if the intruder had left any traces;
带泥的脚印 雪茄头 或是落下的手套 发夹?
muddy foot marks, any cigar end,or dropped glove, hairpin?
什么都没有
There was nothing.
但有个明白的事实
Except the tangible fact
值班员的老婆跑出了大楼
that the Commissioner's wife had run out of the building
就在10分钟前
not ten minutes earlier.
下面你做了什么 费普先生?
What did you do next, Mr. Phelps?
巡警通知了苏格兰场(伦敦警视厅)
The constable alerted Scotland Yard.
然后 我才开始
It was then for the first time
对我的处境感到完全的恐惧
the full horror of my situation came upon me.
我一直有信心找回协定
I'd been so confident of regaining the treaty,
我不敢想象...
I dared not think-
华生会告诉你
Watson will tell you
我在学校是个胆怯敏感的男孩
I was a nervous, sensitive boy at school.
这是我的性格
It's my nature.
我想起叔叔 想起他的内阁同僚
I thought of my uncle, his cabinet colleagues,
想到我给他们和自己带来的耻辱
the shame I'd brought upon them, myself,
也给我的亲友带来耻辱
everyone connected with me.
虽然我是意外事件的受害者
Although I was the victim of an accident,
但外交界是不允许有失误的
there are no allowance for accidents in diplomatic circles.
毁灭
Ruined,
耻辱 绝望的毁灭
shamefully, hopelessly ruined!
稳住 老朋友
Steady on, old chap.
退后 福尔摩斯
Stand back, will you, Holmes.
调查结束了吗?
Is the investigation concluded?
再等等
Adjourned.
可怜的老珀西 对一切紧张过度
Poor old Percy, terrible strain, all this,
事业危在旦夕
career in the balance.
这似乎没有影响令妹的爱
It seems not to have affected your sister's devotion.
她认识费普先生多久了?
How long has she known Mr. Phelps?
他们冬天在诺森伯兰郡认识的
Well, they met in Northumberland in the winter.
珀西当时外出忙政府事务
Percy was traveling on government business
在那个地方
in that part of the world.
他俩一见钟情
It was love at first sight.
你家人认为他俩般配吗?
Do your people approve of the match?
当然 福尔摩斯先生
Indeed, Mr. Holmes,
尤其当他们知道珀西
especially when they learned of Percy's connection
与霍德赫斯勋爵的关系后
with Lord Holdhurst.
我父亲是名铁器制造商
My father is an iron-master,
是保守党的坚定支持者
and a staunch supporter of the Conservative Party.
她来这里是为了见珀西的家人
She came down here to meet Percy's people,
而你陪她一同来?      正确
and you came as escort?      That's right.
在他们离开美国前
just before they left for America.
嗯 婚礼安排在九月举行
The, um, the wedding is planned for September,
只要可怜的小伙子恢复健康
if the poor chap recovers.
我想你本打算作个短暂的拜访
I suppose you only intended a short visit,
结果却发生了这种事?
and then came the smash?
嗯
Mm.
请问你的职业是什么?
May I ask you what your occupation is
为何可以整个夏天都呆在沃金?
that allows you to while away the summer in Woking?
福尔摩斯先生 作为长子
As the eldest son, Mr. Holmes,
我的梦想是继承我父亲生意
I have expectations of inheriting my father's business.
我也涉足于股票
I also dabble in stocks and shares,
因此我有一定的经济独立
which grants me a certain independence.
恕我无礼 如果我的问题得罪了你
My apologies if my question offended you.
5月23日晚上
On the night of May the 23rd,
你约了费普先生在滑铁卢车站见面
had you arranged to meet Mr. Phelps at Waterloo
并一同赶11点的火车吗?
to take the 11:00 o'clock train together?
没有
No.
那是他的打算
That may have been his intention,
他知道我在伦敦跟股票经纪人吃饭
he knew I was in London dining with my stockbroker.
但是我没预计跟他见面
But I wasn't expecting to meet him.
那么谢谢你宝贵的时间 哈里森先生
Then thank you for your time, Mr. Harrison.
我该... 嗯 你能否... 那是病房
Shall I, um, and would you, the sick room.
福尔摩斯先生 真不好意思
Mr. Holmes, I do apologize.
我现在平静多了 多亏了华生的护理
I feel calmer now, thanks to Watson's ministration.
对他温和些 福尔摩斯
Gently with him, Holmes.
啊
Ah.
费普先生
Mr. Phelps,
还有值班员老婆的事
there is just the matter of the Commissioner's wife.
是 当然
Yes, of course.
我记得 我们回办公室后不久
As I remember, shortly after our return to my office,
苏格兰场探员福布斯抵达
Inspector Forbes of the Yard arrived
精神抖擞地接过案子
to take up the case with considerable energy.
我们租了马车 在半个小时内
We hired a hansom, and within half an hour
到了坦盖夫妇位于布莱顿的家
we were at the Tangeys' home in Brixton.
他的大女儿开的门
The door was opened by his eldest daughter.
嘿 你想干嘛?
Hey, what do you want?
你妈妈在家吗?
Is your mother at home?
还没回来
Not yet.
她做晚班的清理活儿
She does a night job - cleaning.
你不介意的话我们在这儿
We'll wait for her, if you don't mind.
等她回来
In here.
你回房 快点 把门关上
And you get back in here, now go on, and shut the door.
大约十分钟后 我们听到前门有动静
After about ten minutes, we heard the front door,
这时我们犯了个严重的错误
and here we made one serious mistake
都怪我不好
for which I blame myself.
妈妈 有两个人在客厅想跟你说话
Mum, there's two men in the parlor wants to talk to ya'.
天啊!
Oh, my God!
这不是办公楼里的费普先生吗?
If it isn't Mr. Phelps of the office.
过来 过来 你以为我们会是谁
Come, come, who did you think we were
让你想逃跑?
when you ran away from us?
我以为你们是执行官
I thought you was the bailiffs.
我们跟个零售商有纠葛
We've had some trouble with a tradesman.
放手 放手 放...
Here, let go, let go, let-
我们有理由相信
We've reason to believe that you've taken
你从外交部拿了份很重要的文件
a paper of importance from the Foreign Office,
你跑到这想销毁文件
and you ran in here to dispose of it.
你最好跟我们去一趟
Now, you better come back with us
苏格兰场接受搜身      把手放开
to Scotland Yard to be searched.        Get your hands off me!
我没有拿文件!      够了...
I didn't take no paper!         That will be enough-
安静下来
There will be peace and quiet.
费普先生...      不要 别!
Mr. Phelps...         no, stop it!
你把厨房搜遍了?
You made a full examination of the kitchen?
是的
Yes.
一点文件的踪迹都没有
There was no sign of the documents.
一架四轮马车来了
A four-wheeler was brought
我们三个一起到了苏格兰场
and we all three drove back in it to Scotland Yard.
我在万分焦急中等待
I waited in an agony of suspense
直到女警察出来报告
until the female searcher came back with her report.
她们什么也没搜到
They found nothing.
之后的事我不太记得了
After that, I have no clear recollection.
我想是位警官送我到滑铁卢
I believe a police officer drove me to Waterloo
稍微走运的是
where by the merest good fortune,
我在那遇到住我附近的费里尔医生
I met Dr. Ferrier, who lives near us
准备乘下一趟火车
and was traveling down by the next train.
你赶上的火车是?
The train you caught now would have been?
11点40分那趟 我想
The 11:40, I think.
费里尔医生我对照顾周到
Dr. Ferrier most kindly took charge of me.
多亏他照顾得好
Just as well he did,
因为我在车站里昏厥过一次
for I had a fit in the station.
在到家之前我几乎成了个语无伦次的疯子
and before we reached home I was practically a raving lunatic.
令兄那时已经回来了吗?
Your brother had already returned?
是的
Yes.
我虽感奇怪 但没有为他独自回来而担忧
I was surprised, but not unduly worried that he was alone.
珀西经常加班 我知道还有另一趟火车
Percy often worked late, and I knew there was another train.
所以我先睡了
So I went to bed.
然后午夜某时?
And sometime after midnight?
我被大厅内可怕的骚动惊醒
I was woken by the most fearful commotion in the hall.
把他带到这 把他带到这!
Bring him in here, bring him in here!
天啊...
Oh, God...
你哥哥当时是在楼下这间房睡觉的?
Your brother was sleeping down here in this room?
是的
Yes.
我家人趁正在美国旅行
My family were taking advantage of their trip to America
让人翻修楼上几间卧室
to have several of the upstairs bedrooms redecorated.
很明显 可怜的珀西病了很久
It was evident that poor Percy was in for a long illness.
所以约瑟搬进我的房间
So, Joseph was bundled up to my room,
这儿变成了我的病房
and this was turned into a sick room for me.
这是个令人愉快的房间
Why, it's a very cheery room.
我在这里已经神志不清地躺了九周
I have lain here for nine weeks, delirious.
如果不是哈里森小姐和医生的照顾
If it had not been for Miss Harrison and the doctor's care,
我现在不可能跟你们说话
I should not be speaking to you now.
她白天护理我
She nursed me by day,
雇佣的护士晚上看我
a hired nurse looked after me at night,
神经病发作时我什么都做不了
for in the mad fits I was capable of anything.
只是数天前
It's only in the last few days
我的神志才慢慢清醒
that my reason has slowly cleared.
我发电报跟福布斯探员联系过
I've wired Inspector Forbes,
但他告诉我 没发现任何线索
but he's told me no clue has been discovered.
所以我找了你 福尔摩斯先生 我最后的希望
So I turn to you, Mr. Holmes, as my last hope.
问一个很重要的问题 费普先生
Just one question of the utmost importance, Mr. Phelps.
你有告诉任何人这个特别任务吗?
Did you tell anyone that you had this special task to perform?
没有
No one.
比如说 哈里森小姐呢?
Not Miss Harrison, for example?
没有
No.
在接到命令和
I had not been back to Woking
执行任务的时间内 我没回过沃金
in between getting the order and executing the commission.
玫瑰是多么可爱的东西呀
What a lovely thing a rose is.
没有什么
There is nothing in which
比宗教更需要推理法
deduction is so necessary as in religion.
推理学者建立出一门精密的学科
It can be built up as an exact science by the reasoner.
我们对上帝仁慈的最高信仰
Our highest assurance of the goodness of Providence
在我看来 尽寄托于鲜花中
seems to me to rest in the flowers.
它额外给予的仁慈
It is only goodness which gives extras,
所以我再说一遍
and so I say again,
我们从花中可得到巨大的希望
we have much to hope for from the flowers.
那你看到解开
Do you see any prospect
这个疑团的希望了吗 福尔摩斯先生?
of solving this mystery, Mr. Holmes?
疑团?
Mystery?
啊 否认这案子难解
Ah, it would be absurd to deny
又复杂的话 那就是愚蠢了
that the case is abstruse and complicated.
你看出什么线索了吗?
Do you see any clue?
你们已经提供了7个线索
You have furnished me with seven,
但是我必须先检验一番
but I must put them to the test
才能判断线索的价值
before I can pronounce on their value.
你怀疑了某人?
You suspect someone?
我怀疑...
I suspect...
我自己
myself.
什么?
What?
是不是过快下结论
Of coming to conclusions too rapidly.
那回伦敦检验你的推论吧!
Then go back to London and test your conclusions!
你的建议很好 哈里森小姐
Your advice is very excellent, Miss Harrison.
费普先生 不要期望太高
Mr. Phelps, do not indulge yourself in false hopes,
此事非常扑朔迷离
the affair is a very tangled one,
而我不是魔术师
and I am not a magician.
嘿 小淘气鬼!
Hey, little varmint!
你怎么看哈里森小姐?
What do you think of Miss Harrison?
还不错 要么我看错了
A good sort, or I'm mistaken.
我觉得你对她直接了些
I thought you were rather terse with her.
是吗?
Was I?
她只是在保护爱人
She was only protecting her loved one.
也许保护过头了点
A little overprotective, perhaps.
当然 你不会以为
Surely, you don't believe
她与此事有关吧?
that she had anything to do with it?
华生 最难侦查的犯罪
The most difficult crime to track down, Watson,
就是毫无目的的犯罪
is the one which is purposeless.
而这个并非毫无目的
Now, this is not purposeless,
那么谁是此事的受益人?
but who is it that profits by it?
法国大使 俄国大使
Well, there's the French Ambassador, the Russian,
把协定卖给其中一位大使的人
and whoever might sell it to either of those.
还有霍德赫斯勋爵
And Lord Holdhurst.
这不是不可能
While it is not inconceivable
一个政治家处于如此地位
that a statesman might find himself in a position
就不会后悔
where he was not sorry
能趁机毁掉这么一份文件
to see such a document accidentally destroyed.
但拥有光荣记录
Not a statesman
的霍德赫斯勋爵不是这样的政治家
with the honorable record of Lord Holdhurst.
乔治 去外交部
George, the Foreign Office,
查尔斯街入口
Charles Street entrance.
乔治 我想你为我做点事
George, I want you to do something for me.
找一架曾在那儿下车的马车
Find the cab which dropped a fare there
时间是5月23日晚刚过9点半
just after half past 9:00 on the evening of May the 23rd.
戈罗 法国名字
Gorot, a French name.
实际是胡格诺教徒
Huguenot, actually.
但我跟你一样是英国人 福尔摩斯先生
But I'm as English in sympathy as you are, Mr. Holmes.
我是否因为姓名而遭怀疑?
Am I under some sort of cloud because of my name?
哦 不 不 福尔摩斯也有个法国奶奶
Oh, no, no, Holmes has a French grandmother.
我可以让你躲开
I'd make yourself scarce
福布斯探员的调查 如果你想的话
if you want to avoid Inspector Forbes.
我们安排了他5分钟后于此见面
We've arranged to meet him here in five minutes.
是的 我已经被他讯问过
Yes, I have been questioned by him already.
我会照你们说的做
I shall do as you say.
两位 晚安
Goodnight to you both.
晚安
Goodnight.
没有暗门
No secret doors,
窗户距地面30英尺
the windows quite 30 feet above the ground,
从里面插上插销
fastened on the inner side.
地毯使地板门的可能性为零
The carpet prevents any possibility of a trap door.
无论是谁拉铃绳
Now, whoever rang the bell rope
都必须来到这个桌子前面
must have come right over to the desk.
为什么拉铃呢?
Why ring it?
这个小偷想虚张声势?
I mean, was it the thief, out of bravado?
或是有谁跟小偷一块儿
Or was it someone with the thief
他想阻止这个罪行?
who tried to prevent the crime?
要么就...
Or was it-
是福布斯探员 对吗?
Inspector Forbes, I believe.
福尔摩斯先生 我是个大忙人
Mr. Holmes, I'm a very busy man.
除了这个我还有别的案件
I have other cases besides this one.
但我打赌没什么比国家利益更重要
But none so vital to the national interest, I'll wager.
我来介绍一下我的朋友兼同事 华生医生
May I introduce my friend and colleague, Dr. Watson?
你想从我这知道什么 福尔摩斯?
What do you want from me, Holmes?
我知道你的那一套
I know about your methods.
你准备用我们的情报
You're ready enough to use our information,
自己设法去结案
then you try and finish the case yourself
然后让我们丢人现眼
and bring discredit on us.
正相反 在我破获的53件案子里
On the contrary, in my last 53 cases,
只有4件提到我的名字
my name has appeared in only 4
其他49件功劳全归警方
and the police have the credit in 49.
我不责怪你不知道这个
I don't blame you for not knowing this,
你年轻 缺乏经验
you are young and inexperienced.
但如果你想在工作上出人头地
But if you wish to get on in your duties
你得跟我合作 而不是对着干
you will work with me and not against me!
那你采取过什么措施?
Now, then, what steps have you taken?
坦盖 那个值班员 我们查过了
Tangey, the commissioner, we've cleared.
他离开警卫队时名声很好
He left the Guards with a good character.
但他老婆不是好东西 酗酒
His wife is a bad lot, though, she drinks.
那个职员戈罗呢?
What about the clerk, Gorot?
我们已经跟踪他九周了
He's been shadowed all these nine weeks.
还是找不到任何线索
We can show nothing against him.
你对铃为什么会响有何看法?
Have you formed any theory about how this bell rang?
没有
No.
我得承认 我被难倒了
I must confess, that beats me.
不管是谁干的 那人都很厚颜无耻
It was a cool hand, whoever it was,
来了还发警报
to go and give the alarm like that.
对 是件很奇怪的事情
Yes, yes, it was a very queer thing to do.
好的 非常感谢 探员
Well, many thanks, Inspector,
如果我要你去抓那个贼
and if I can put this thief in your hands,
我会通知你的
you shall hear from me.
走吧 华生
Come along, Watson.
能问一下你们现在去哪里?
May I ask where you're going now?
跟内阁大臣霍德赫斯勋爵会面
To interview Lord Holdhurst, the Cabinet Minister
他很可能是下一届英格兰首相
and very possibly the next Premier of England.
晚安 探员
Good evening, Inspector.
福尔摩斯先生
I can't pretend, Mr. Holmes,
我不能装作不知你的来意
that I am ignorant of the reason for your visit,
但能否问下你是在为谁效力?
but in whose interests are you acting, may I ask?
受珀西・费普先生所托
In the part of Mr. Percy Phelps.
啊 我不幸的侄子
Ah, my unfortunate nephew.
你知道我们的血缘关系
You can understand that our kinship
无论如何都让我无法包庇他
makes it the more impossible for me to screen him in any way.
但如果文件找到了呢 霍德赫斯勋爵?
Yes, but if the document is found, Lord Holdhurst?
那当然另当别论
That, of course, would be different.
霍德赫斯勋爵 您是在
Lord Holdhurst, it was in this room
这间办公室吩咐抄写文件的吗?
that you gave instructions for the copying of the document?
是的
It was.
除了贵侄子外您没有对外人提起过
And you mentioned it to nobody else except your nephew,
您确定吗?
you're certain of that?
很确定
Absolutely.
那么如果别人不知道
Then if nobody else knew of it,
您承认小偷出现在你侄子办公室
you would agree that the thief's presence in your nephew's room
纯属偶然了
was purely accidental.
那他是顺手拿走文件的
I mean, he saw his chance and took it.
你说的超出我能力范围 福尔摩斯先生
You take me out of my province there, Mr. Holmes.
还有重要的一点...
There is one other very important point.
您很担心 而我认为
You feared, so I understand,
如果协定的细节
that very grave results
一经外泄 其后果极为严重
might follow from the details of this treaty becoming known?
的确是很严重的后果
Very grave results indeed.
后果产生了吗?
Have they occurred?
还没有
Not yet.
我们假设 如果此协定已经落入
If the treaty had reached, let us say,
俄国或法国外交部手中
the Russian or the French Foreign Office,
你认为你收得到风声吗?
you would expect to hear of it?
我当然可以
I certainly should.
既然将近十周过去了
Then since nearly ten weeks have elapsed,
那有正当理由假设
it is not unfair to suppose then
由于某种原因协定还没落入他们之手
that the treaty for some reason has not reached them.
可是福尔摩斯 我们很难假设
But Holmes, we can hardly suppose
小偷盗协定是为了...
that the thief took the treaty in order to...
裱起来挂在墙上
frame it and hang it on his wall.
也许他在等更高的价钱 华生
Well, perhaps he's waiting for a better price, Watson.
或是他突然病了
Or maybe he's had a sudden illness.
比如 神经失常?
A brain storm, for example?
我没这样说
I did not say so.
霍德赫斯勋爵 我们已经
Lord Holdhurst, we have
占用了你很多宝贵时间
taken up too much of your valuable time.
不错的人 责任心很强
Fine fellow, heavy responsibilities.
是的 可他要抱住官职 仍需一番努力
Yes, but he has a struggle to keep up his position,
而且他远不富有
and he's far from rich.
你肯定注意到他的靴子换过鞋底
You noticed, of course, that his boots had been resoled.
是吗?
Really?!
今天没什么再能做了
I shall do nothing more today
除非我寻找马车那事有回音
unless I get an answer to my cab inquiry.
啊
Ah.
好的
All right.
哦 华生 我不会耽误太久
Oh, Watson, I won't detain you any longer
你的正经工作时间
from your legitimate work.
但是我会万分感激
But I should be extremely obliged
如果你明天能陪我去一趟沃金
if you would come down to Woking with me tomorrow,
跟今天坐的火车同班次
the same train that we took today.
好的 当然
Yes, of course.
晚安 福尔摩斯
Goodnight, Holmes.
不 不 今晚我独自一人睡
No, no, tonight I shall sleep my own sleep, and alone.
但是 珀西...
But Percy.
福尔摩斯先生给了我新的希望
Mr. Holmes has imbued me with fresh hope,
我觉得我有好转了
and I feel I'm on the mend.
我们预约九月份去教堂 亲爱的
We have an appointment in church in September, my love,
我不想取消预约
and I mean to keep it.
他让护士离开了
He sent the nurse away.
终于
At last.
他太信任那个大侦探
He puts too much faith in the great detective.
是你让他有生机
It's you that's kept his flame alive,
不是什么侦探
not some detective.
还有你 哥哥
And you, brother.
没有你支持我的话
Without you to support me-
可能我成了某个可怕阴谋的中心
Could it be that I am the center of some monstrous conspiracy,
他们的目标不仅是我的荣誉 还有我的命?
and that my life is aimed at, as well as my honor?
据我所知 我在这世上没有仇敌!
I haven't as far as I know, an enemy in the world!
你肯定只是不走运 老朋友
You certainly have had your share of misfortune, old chap.
我想我找到现场了
I think I may have found the spot
那家伙从这翻墙而过!
where the fella' scaled the wall!
这里通向马路
It's towards the road.
你觉得这是昨晚做的吗?
Ah, do you think this was done last night?
我看是老痕迹了
It looks rather old to me.
不 我想在这找不到什么线索
No, I fancy we shall get no help there.
为什么入侵者
Now, why did the intruder
选择爬面对庭院的窗而入?
choose the window onto the courtyard?
我觉得
I should have thought
从房子这边进去更容易才是
this side of the house would have been easier.
从庭院看这里更清楚
It's more visible from the courtyard.
啊 是的 当然
Ah, yes, of course.
你们以前受过这种惊吓吗?
Have you ever had an alarm like this before?
屋子里没什么金银餐具
There's no plate in the house,
或其它招引盗贼的东西?
or anything to attract burglars?
没什么值钱的
Nothing of value.
伦敦的调查如何?
Was there anything in London?
我们跟福布斯探员见过
Well, we've seen Inspector Forbes,
还见过你叔叔
we've seen your uncle.
福尔摩斯已经有了一两个行动
Holmes has set one or two things in motion.
你们还没放弃
So you've not lost heart.
哦 绝对不会!
Oh, by no means!
上帝保佑你这么说
God bless you for saying that.
只要我们保持耐心和勇气
If we keep our courage and patience,
真相会水落石出的
the truth must come out.
哈里森小姐
Miss Harrison,
你后面几天一定要守在这房间里
you must remain in this room for the rest of the day.
这个非常重要
It is of vital importance.
今晚 你临睡前
Now, tonight, when you go to bed,
从外面锁上那扇门 并保留着钥匙
lock that door from the outside and keep the key.
但是珀西?       别对任何人说
But Percy?        Tell no one!
马上向我保证!
Now, quick, promise!
为什么你在这没精打采 亲爱的?
Why are you moping in here, honey?
出来晒晒太阳
Come out in the sunshine.
我愿陪你走走
I'll be your crockie.
我有点头痛
I have a slight headache
这个房间挺凉爽舒服
and this room is deliciously cool and soothing,
谢谢 约瑟
thank you, Joseph.
费普先生 尽管这件小事也要调查
Mr. Phelps, while we're investigating this minor affair
但我们绝不能忽视主要的任务
we must not lose sight of our main inquiry.
如果你能跟我们去一趟伦敦
It would help me very much
将会对我有很大帮助
if you would come up to London with us.
你感觉身体硬朗些了吗?
Do you feel strong enough?
好的 如果你真觉得我能帮上忙的话
Yes, if you really think I can be of help.
你想我在那待过夜吗?
Do you want me to stay the night?
我正想如此建议
I was on the point of proposing it.
如果那位夜间不速之客来访
Then if my friend of the night comes to visit me,
他只能无功而返
he'll find the bird flown.
但安妮怎么办?
But, what about Annie?
啊 哈里森先生会照看她的
Ah, Mr. Harrison will look after her,
我的朋友华生会护理你的
and my friend Watson will take care of your medical needs.
一小时内能准备好出发吗?
Could you be ready to leave in an hour?
一切听从你的 福尔摩斯先生
We are all in your hands, Mr. Holmes.
有一两件事我要说明
There are one or two points I wish to clear up,
费普先生 你不在这 反而帮了我的忙
and your absence, Mr. Phelps, will rather assist me.
华生 到伦敦后
Watson, when you reach London
送我们的朋友直接到贝克街
drive our friend straight to Baker Street
一直陪着他直到我跟你们见面
and remain with him until I see you again.
现在 先生们 我要走了
And now, gentlemen, I shall leave you.
我们在伦敦的调查怎么办?
What about our investigation in London?!
我希望能及时赶回伦敦吃早餐
I hope to be in London in time for breakfast.
他真是个深不可测的家伙 华生
He really is the most inscrutable fellow, Watson.
哦 你还在这里
Oh, you're still in here.
你的头痛怎么样了?
How's your headache?
好一些了
A little better.
九周来第一次没有病人在身边
The first day for nine weeks without the invalid,
你却仍选择待在这里
and you choose to spend it in here.
习惯的力量
Force of habit.
吃晚饭吗?
Are you dining tonight?
我不饿 我想看书
I'm not hungry, and I'm enjoying my book.
嗯 我懂
Mm, I understand.
我可怜的妹妹 你经历了不少呀
My poor little sister, what a time you've had.
福尔摩斯先生回来了 先生
That'll be Mr. Holmes returning now, sir.
谢谢 霍乐斯
Thank you, Horace.
他似乎精疲力竭了
He looks like a beaten man.
我承认你说对了
I confess you may be right.
我期望过高了
I'd hoped for so much!
福尔摩斯 你受伤了!
Holmes, you're wounded!
哦 只是自己不小心擦伤的
Oh, it's only a scratch through my own clumsiness.
早上好 费普先生 你的案件
Good morning, Mr. Phelps, this case of yours
是我办理过最黑暗的一宗
is certainly one of the darkest I have ever investigated.
这是一次非同一般的经历
It has been a remarkable experience.
快说吧 福尔摩斯 那绷带说明你冒过险
Oh, come along, Holmes, that bandage tells of adventures.
发生什么了?
Now, what happened?
先吃早餐 亲爱的华生
After breakfast, my dear Watson.
别忘了我今早可是
Remember, I have breathed
从萨里赶了30英里的路回来
30 miles of Surrey air this morning.
我想 我寻马车的事还没回音吧?
There's been no answer to my cab inquiry, I suppose?
不会每次都那么走运
Well, one cannot score every time.
哈德森夫人 你总是应对自如
Mrs. Hudson, you have risen to the occasion.
一起来吧 费普先生?
Won't you join us, Mr. Phelps?
那是什么?
Now, what's in this?
咖喱鸡 先生
Curried chicken, sir.
这个呢?
And this?
火腿和鸡蛋
Ham and eggs.
她会做的菜不太多
Her cuisine is a little limited,
但像所有苏格兰女人 她的早餐搭配得妙
but she has as good an idea of breakfast as any Scotswoman.
你想吃什么 费普先生 咖喱鸡 鸡蛋
Now, what will you take, Mr. Phelps, curried fowl, eggs,
请自己来
or will you help yourself?
谢谢 我什么都不想吃
Thank you. I can eat nothing.
哦 请尝尝你前面那盘子里的菜
Oh, please, try the dish before you.
谢谢 我真的不想吃
Thank you, I would really rather not.
我想你不会不愿意帮我忙吧?
Oh, well, then, I suppose you have no objection to helping me?
哦!
Oh!
是协定
It's the treaty.
天啊 这是协定!
My God, it's the treaty!
这是协定!
It's the treaty!
华生 白兰地
Watson, brandy.
啊 好啦 好啦 好啦
Ah, there, there, there,
我太坏了 不该突然放到你面前
it really was too bad of me to spring it on you like that,
但是华生会告诉你
but Watson here will tell you
我总忍不住来点戏剧性的变化
that I never can resist a touch of the dramatic.
上帝保佑你 挽救了我的荣誉
God bless you for saving my honor.
谢谢你 哈德森夫人
Thank you, Mrs. Hudson.
哦 谢谢你如此体贴
Oh, thank you for your many considerations.
苏格兰妇人的早餐 只是几张傻纸张!
A Scotswoman's breakfast, indeed, a silly bit of paper!
请告诉我 你是如何找到的?
Please, tell me how you got it, where it was!
离开你们后
After I left you,
我走到英格兰的乡村
I settled myself into the English countryside
享受可爱的下午
and spent a charming afternoon.
我在那里待到黄昏
I remained there until dusk,
然后回到你的房子
and then I returned to your house.
我翻过墙
I clambered over the wall
穿过小丛林
and made my way through the undergrowth
直到去到马厩
until I reached the stables,
刚好在你卧室窗户对面
just opposite your bedroom window.
你房间的百叶窗还没被拉起
The blind in your window had not yet been drawn,
我能看到哈里森小姐
and I could see Miss Harrison reading a book
在油灯下读书
by the light from a lamp.
她合上书时是10点15分
It was about a quarter-past ten when she closed the book,
走过房间 手里拿着油灯
moved across the room, carrying the lamp with her.
我清楚知道 她扭转在门上的钥匙
But I felt quite sure that she had turned the key in the lock.
钥匙?
Key?
是我给她的指示
The instructions I gave her,
她都一一做到
which she carried out to the letter.
费普先生 她是位有可贵性格的女士
Mr. Phelps, she is a lady of rare character.
没有她的合作
Without her cooperation,
你手里就不会拿着文件了
you would not have that paper in your hand now.
艰辛的守夜
It was a weary vigil,
但是有种冒险者躺在
but it had the sort of excitement a sportsman feels
河道前 等着大猎物时
when he lies before the watercourse
的兴奋心情
and waits for the big game.
发生什么了 发生什么了?
What happened, what happened?!
大概临晨两点左右
It was about 2:00 o'clock in the morning,
我听到轻微推开插销的声音
when I heard the gentle sound of a bolt being pushed back.
好了
All right.
好了 福尔摩斯 你想对我怎么样?
All right, Holmes, what you gonna do with me?
我得到我想要的了
I've got what I want.
哇!      滚
Ow!        Run.
约瑟!
Joseph!
你让他跑了?
You let him go?!
我用电报告知了福布斯探员所有细节
I wired full particulars to Inspector Forbes.
如果他能迅速去抓犯人 那就没问题
If he's quick enough to catch his bird, well and good.
不过我倒怀疑犯人已经人去楼空
But if, as I shrewdly suspect, he finds the nest empty,
不过这样对政府来说反而更好
why, all the better for the government.
我想不但霍德赫斯勋爵
I fancy Lord Holdhurst, for one,
而且珀西・费普先生
and Mr. Percy Phelps for another,
都不想让这案子上治安法庭吧
would much rather the affair never got to a police court.
天啊 你是说在这十周的痛苦经历中
My God, do you tell me that during my 10 long weeks of agony
被盗的文件一直在我身边?
the stolen papers were in the very room with me all the time?
而约瑟 恶棍 小偷!
And Joseph, a villain and a thief!
据我所知 他在股票投资中损失了一大笔钱
From what I gather, he had lost heavily dabbling in stocks,
还隐瞒着他父亲
and concealed the fact from his father,
他父亲是个严守旧观念的人
a man of strictly conservative habits.
可他为此践踏亲生妹妹的幸福
Yes, but his own sister's happiness,
还有你的名声和健康!
and your reputation, your health!
他知道你常工作到很晚
He knew that you often worked late,
他当时在城里和股票投资商共进晚餐
and he was in town having dinner with his stockbroker,
他对我提过
as he told me.
但他到九点半就没事做了
But he was free by half past 9:00,
便顺路去你的办公室 从侧门进去
and called by your office, entering through the side door.
珀西?
Percy?
他看没人
Finding no one in there
灯却亮着 很明显工作还没结束
but the light on and work evidently in progress,
他拉了铃
he rang the bell.
那瞬间 他看到你桌子上的文件
The instant he did so, his eye caught the paper on the table.
他马上意识到这是一个机会
He knew at once that chance had put in his way
一个极有价值的官方文件
a state document of immense value,
他一个人回到沃金
returned alone to Woking
并把文件藏到自认为很安全的地方
and concealed it in what he thought was a very safe place,
打算在一两天后转移它
intending to remove it in a day or two,
然后送到法国大使馆
and take it to the French embassy
或卖给能出高价的地方
or wherever he thought a long price was to be had.
那里没人 那里没人!
There's nobody there, there's nobody there!
然后你突然回来
Then came your sudden return.
他毫无预兆地被要求搬出房间
Without a moment's warning he was bundled out of his room
从那一刻起
and from that moment on,
那房间总是有至少你俩在
there were always at least two of you in there,
妨碍了他取回宝贝 让他很恼火
preventing him from regaining his treasure, maddening for him.
我的怀疑变成肯定
My suspicions became certainties
当有人企图在让护士
when the attempt to break in
离开的头天晚上闯入房间
was made on the first night that the hired nurse was absent,
就表示了入侵者
which showed that the intruder
非常熟悉那个家的情况
was well accustomed with the ways of the house.
最终 他的机会来了
At last, he had his chance.
但你的醒来又吓跑了他
But you baffled him with your wakefulness.
是的 我没有喝安眠药!
Yes! I didn't take my sleeping draft!
但你来伦敦让他又有一次机会
But he had another chance when you came up to London.
我让哈里森小姐
I kept Miss Harrison
整天待在房里 以防他提前下手
in the room all day so as to anticipate him.
可既然你知道文件在房间里?
But if you already knew the papers were in the room?
我只是假设有可能
I thought they probably were,
我可不想拆开所有壁脚
but I had no desire to rip up all the skirting
来找文件
in search of them.
让他引我知道藏处
By allowing him to lead me to the hiding place,
节省了我大量功夫
I saved myself an infinity of trouble.
还能逮个正着!
And caught him red-handed!
正确
Quite so.
但他为什么要从窗户进来
Yes, but why did he try the window
他也能从正门进来呀?
when he might have come in through the door?
他想假装是外贼 可以的话
To appear to be a burglar, and if necessary,
他想从庭院逃跑出去
make good his escape across the courtyard.
刀子
The knife,
他是不是有杀人的企图?
you don't think he had any murderous intentions?
亲爱的朋友
My dear fellow,
我不相信约瑟・哈里森先生
I can only say that Mr. Joseph Harrison is a gentleman
是肯大发善心的君子
to whose mercy I should be extremely unwilling to trust.
一位年轻女士来找你了 费普先生
That will be a young lady for you, Mr. Phelps.
安妮!
Annie!
我给她留了口信 醒来后来伦敦
I left her a note to come to London the moment she woke.
但是费普先生
But Mr. Phelps,
她一点都不知道她哥哥的罪行
she knows nothing as yet of her brother's criminality.
哦 好的
Oh, yes.
亲爱的福尔摩斯 真是感激不尽
My dear Holmes, I can't thank you enough.
我要立即下去解释这一切
I shall go down at once and explain everything.
珀西 再见 祝你好运!
Percy, good-bye, and good luck!
谢谢你挽救了我的幸福
Thank you for restoring my happiness.
门口有位年轻女士 先生
There's a young lady at the door, sir.
福尔摩斯先生 热水!
Mr. Holmes, hot water!
谢谢
Thank you.
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-